Guide to the Benét Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Benét Family Papers
1836-1994
YCAL MSS 1107
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
26.65
56 boxes
Benét Family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired through gift and purchase from Laura Benét, Thomas Benét, and Rebecca (Benét) Sawyer, 1977-2017.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 55: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Box 56 (videocassette): Restricted fragile material. Reference copy may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Benét family
Brigadier General S. V. (Stephen Vincent) Benét was born 22 January 1827 in St. Augustine, Florida. He studied at Hallowell's school in Alexandria, Virginia and then at the University of Georgia and the United States Military Academy, where he graduated in 1849. He was appointed to the Ordnance Corps, and served at the Watervliet Arsenal, at Washington, at Frankford Arsenal, again at Washington, and then at the St. Louis Arsenal. In 1859 he became Assistant Professor of Geography, History, and Ethics at West Point, and from 1861 until 1864 was instructor of Ordnance and the Science of Gunnery. From 1865 until 1869 he was in command of Frankford arsenal. In 1869 he became Assistant to the Chief of Ordnance, and in 1874 he succeeded to Chief of Ordnance with the rank of Brigadier General. He translated Jomini's Political and Military History of the Campaign of Waterloo (New York, 1853) and he is the author of a treatise on "Military Law and the Practice of Courts-Martial" (1862) and "Electro-Ballistic Machines and the Schultze Chronoscope" (1866).
He married Laura Amanda Walker and together they had two sons, James Walker Benét and Laurence Vincent Benét.
James Walker Benét (1857-1928), a Colonel in the U.S. Army, was born 16 July, 1857 in Richmond, Kentucky. He graduated from West Point Academy in 1880 and went on to serve most of his military career in the Army Ordnance Department. From 1890 until his retirement in 1921, he served at the Frankford Arsenal, Philadelphia (1890-1984); Bethlehem Iron Works, South Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (1894-1898); Ordnance Headquarters, Buffalo, New York (1898-1899); Watervliet Arsenal, New York (1904-1905, 1919-1921); Rock Island Arsenal, Illinois (1904-1905), Benicia Arsenal, California (1905-1911), and Augusta Arsenal, Georgia (1911-1918).
James Walker Benét married Frances Neill Rose (1860-1940) of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania in 1883. Ms. Rose, born 23 October, 1860 in Washington, D.C., was the child of William John Rose and Mary Lee Mahon. She attended Mrs. Sutton's School for Girls. Their children include authors Laura Benét, William Rose Benét, and Stephen Vincent Benét.
Laura Benét (1884-1979) was educated at the Emma Willard School in Troy, New York, and at Vassar and Moravian colleges. She worked at the Spring Street Settlement in New York City from 1915 to 1917 and at the American Red Cross in Augusta, Georgia from 1917 to 1919. She later took on editorial and free-lance writing assignments. She was the author of several poetry collections, fiction, and biographical works.
William Rose Benét (1886-1950) was educated at Albany Academy and Yale College (1903-1907). After college, Benét worked for Century Magazine as a reader. He served in the U.S. Air Services during the First World War, and after the war took work as a copy writer for an advertising firm. In 1920, Henry Seidel Canby brought Benét on as an assistant editor at the New York Evening Post and in 1923, Canby, Benét, and their fellow editors left the Post to form the Saturday Review.
William Rose Benét was the author of several collections of poetry, a novel, and a collection of essays. His autobiography in verse, The Dust Which Is God (1941), was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1942. In addition to his long-standing (1923-1950) position with the Saturday Review, Benét contributed to several compilations of English-language poetry and literature.
William Rose Benét married four times, to: Teresa Frances Thomson (1912-1919), with whom he had three children, James Walker Benét (1914-2012), Kathleen Anne (Benét) Fry, and Frances Rosemary (Benét) Dawson; poet Elinor Wylie (1923-1928); actress Lora Baxter (1932-1937); and children's book author Majorie Flack (1941-1950).
Stephen Vincent Benét (1898-1943), educated at Summerville Academy and Yale College (1915-1919), was a well known and widely read author in the United States during the 1930s and 1940s. After the success of his long poem, John Brown's Body (1928), for which he was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1929, he regularly published poems, short stories, and other work in popular magazines such as The Atlantic Monthly, The New Yorker, and The Saturday Evening Post. His short story, "The Devil and Daniel Webster" (1936) was awarded the O. Henry Memorial Award in 1937. In addition to poetry and short stories, he is the author of novels, book reviews, essays, radio and stage plays, screenplays, and speeches.
Stephen Vincent Benét and Rosemary Carr married in 1921. They had three children, Thomas, Stephanie Jane, and Rachel.
Biographical information taken from Arlington National Cemetary website and other sources.
Scope and Contents
The Benét family papers consists of correspondence, manuscripts, and other papers documenting the lives and activities of four generations of the Benét family. Material relating to members of the Rose, Mahon, and Carr families can also be found. The collection spans the years from 1849 to 1994.
The defining thread to the collection runs from Brigadier General Stephen Vincent Benét and his wife Laura Amanda (Walker) Benét through their son James Walker Benét and his wife Frances Neill (Rose) Benét, through their three children, Laura, William Rose, and Stephen Vincent, to the children of William Rose and Stephen Vincent Benét.
The three siblings, Laura, William Rose, and Stephen Vincent established the Benét family's literary reputation in the early to mid-20th century. The papers of Laura Benét are particularly well represented here. The Correspondence series includes large files of letters to Laura Benét from her mother and her two brothers. The Writings series includes over 50 examples of her work, with drafts and printed versions of short forms such as poems, reviews, stories, and essays. And the Other Papers series includes 26 diary volumes dating from 1922 to 1978, as well as scrapbooks and other material.
Collection material is chiefly in English; with some material in French.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1854-1994. II. Writings, 1849-1973. III. Other Papers, 1871-1994.
Related Materials
Material by or relating to the Benét family acquired by the library from non-family sources is located in the Benét Family Collection (YCAL MSS 1108). Additional material by or relating to Stephen Vincent and Rosemary Benét can be found in the Stephen Vincent Benét and Rosemary Benét Papers (YCAL MSS 1046). Additional material by or relating to William Rose Benét can be found in the William Rose Benét Papers (YCAL MSS 1100).
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Benét, James, 1914-; Benét, Frances Rose, 1860-1940; Benét, James, 1914-; Benet, James Walker, 1914-; Benét, Laura; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Carr family; Mahan family; Rose family; Benet, James Walker, 1914-; Benét, Laura; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Benét, Frances Rose, 1860-1940; Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benet, Thomas; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Benét family
- Correspondence, 1854-1994; 1880-1940s; 13.34; 32 boxes
  Arrangement
  Organized into 28 subseries. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically first by correspondent (recipient) and then by sender. Letters are arranged chonologically within files.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Correspondence is the largest component of the Benét family papers. The correspondence covers four generations of the family, almost 150 years, dating from the mid-19th century (1854) to the end of the 20th century (1994). The defining thread of the series, and indeed the entire collection, runs from Brigadier General Stephen Vincent Benét and his wife Laura Amanda (Walker) Benét through their son James Walker Benét and his wife Frances Neill (Rose) Benét, through their three children, Laura, William Rose, and Stephen Vincent, to, finally, the children of William Rose and Stephen Vincent Benét.
  The three siblings, Laura, William Rose, and Stephen Vincent established the family's literary reputation in the early to mid-20th century, and there are large files of letters from the three children to their mother, Frances Rose Benét. There are also large files of letters to Laura Benét from her mother and from her brother William Rose. Additionally, there are letters to and from more extended members of the family, including the Rose, Mahon, and Carr families. Other noteworthy files exist for Rosemary Benét and her mother, Dr. Rachel H. Carr of Chicago, Illinois.
  - Frances Rose Benét Correspondence
    - Baxter, Lora, 1933 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1922 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Benét, James, 1914-, 1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Benét, Laura, 1907-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Benét, Laurence Vincent, 1928 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Benét, Margaret Cox, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Benét, Rosemary, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1909–1936 (Box 1, Folder 10-17)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1936-1940, undated (Box 2, Folder 18-28)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1905–1916 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1917-1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 31-33)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), 1927-1939, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét), 1928, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Mahon, John M., undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Mahon, Mary, 1925–1928 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - [Norris?], Kathleen Thompson, 1918 August (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Peterson, Anne, 1928 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Rose, Elizabeth Neill, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - [Rose?], Genevieve, 1928 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Rose, Mary Lee (Mahon), 1906 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Rose, Mary, 1935 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Rose, William John, 1928 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Others, 1910–1937 (Box 3, Folder 46-51)
      Includes letters from Frances Rose Benét
    - Others, undated (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
    - Empty envelopes, 1906-1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 54-56)
  - James Walker Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1893-1927, undated (Box 4, Folder 57-59)
    - Benét, James, 1914-, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Benét, Laura, 1925-1927, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Benét, Laura Amanda (Walker), 1876 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Benét, Laurence Vincent, 1900-1919, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Benét, Margaret Cox, 1916–1927 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1927 October 31 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1876 September 26 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1912, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1904–1928 (Box 5, Folder 68-69)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), 1923, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét), 1927 April 1 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Rose, Elizebeth Neill, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Others, 1900-1928, undated (Box 5, Folder 73-74)
      Includes letters from James Walker Benét
  - James Benét Correspondence
    - Norris, Kathleen Thompson, undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Others, 1922, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Laura Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1906-1937, undated (Box 5, Folder 77-84)
    - Benét, Frances Rose, undated (Box 6, Folder 85-86)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1905-1927, undated (Box 6, Folder 87-88)
    - Benét, James, 1914-, 1919-1926, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Benét, Margaret Cox, 1923 December 24 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Benét, Peter, 1966 September 5 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1921-1943, undated (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1913-1942, undated (Box 6, Folder 93-96)
    - Benét, Thomas, 1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1906–1939 (Box 6, Folder 98-100)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1940-1949, undated (Box 7, Folder 101-108)
      Includes third party correspondence
    - Dawson, Bill, 1964 December 29 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), 1923-1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 110-111)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét), 1919-1953, undated (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Mahin, Stephanie, undated (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Mahon, Agnes, 1904-1927, undated (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Mahon, Mary, 1919 September 11 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - Norris, Charles G. (Charles Gilman), undated (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Rose, William John, 1923 December 19 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - Others, 1891-1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 118-126)
      Includes letters from Laura Benét
    - Others, undated (Box 9, Folder 127-129)
  - Laura Amanda (Walker) Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1856 February 24 (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - Laurence Vincent Benét Correspondence
    - Others, 1906, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - Rachel Benét Correspondence
    - Carr, Rachel H., undated (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - Rosemary Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1921, undated (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Benét, James Walker, undated (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Benét, Laura, 1922 January 16 (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1926, undated (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1901–1920 (Box 9, Folder 137-145)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1920–1933 (Box 10, Folder 146-159)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1933-1938, undated (Box 11, Folder 160-161)
    - Carr, Thomas, 1919–1921 (Box 11, Folder 162-163)
    - McVey, Margaret, 1910, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - Mahon, Agnes, 1920 May (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Others, [1915?]-1943, undated (Box 11, Folder 166-169)
  - S. V. (Stephen Vincent) Benét Correspondence
    - Others, 1854-188[4?] (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Stephanie Benét Correspondence
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1926-1931, undated (Box 11, Folder 171)
  - Stephen Vincent Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, [1905?], 1918 (Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1904, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Benét, James, 1914-, 1928 September 18 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Benét, Laurence Vincent, 1918 March 18 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Benét, Rosemary, undated (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1916-1918, undated (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1921-1933, undated (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Others, 1907–1917 (Box 11, Folder 179)
  - Teresa (Thomson) Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1912 August 14 (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1912 August (Box 11, Folder 181)
  - Thomas Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Laura, 1963 April 16 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1926-1934, undated (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Others, 1993-1994, undated (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - William Rose Benét Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, undated (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, undated (Box 12, Folder 186)
    - Hoyt, Henry Martyn, undated (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - Others, 19[17?]-1926, undated (Box 12, Folder 188)
      Includes letters from William Rose Benét
  - Rachel H. Carr Correspondence
    - [Bailey?], Mary Josephine, 1908, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1921-1934, undated (Box 12, Folder 190-194)
    - Benét, Rachel, 1934 February 15 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1905–1920 (Box 12, Folder 196-199)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1920–1926 (Box 13, Folder 200-209)
      Includes photographs and clippings
    - Clippings removed from Benét, Rosemary, 1921, undated (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 716-717)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1926–1928 (Box 14, Folder 210-219)
      Includes photographs
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1928–1930 (Box 15, Folder 220-229)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1931–1933 (Box 16, Folder 230-239)
      Includes third party correspondence, photographs, and clippings
    - Clipping removed from Benét, Rosemary, 1931 November 14 (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 718)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1934–1938 (Box 17, Folder 240-251)
    - Clipping removed from Benét, Rosemary, 1934 July 1 (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 719)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1938, undated (Box 18, Folder 252-255)
    - Clippings removed from Benét, Rosemary, undated (Box 53 (Oversize), Folder 720)
    - Benét, Rosemary (letters to Rachel and Thomas Carr), 1910–1920 (Box 18, Folder 256-263)
      Includes third party correspondence, photographs, and printed material
    - Benét, Rosemary (letters to Rachel and Thomas Carr), 1920–1924 (Box 19, Folder 264-274)
    - Benét, Rosemary (letters to Rachel and Thomas Carr), 1924-1929, undated (Box 20, Folder 275-285)
    - Benét, Rosemary (letters to Rachel and Thomas Carr), undated (Box 21, Folder 286)
    - Benét, Stephanie; Benét, Thomas, 1933–1934 (Box 21, Folder 287)
    - Benét, Stephanie, 1933-1938, undated (Box 21, Folder 288)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1921-1936, undated (Box 21, Folder 289-292)
    - Benét, Thomas, 1934-1938, undated (Box 21, Folder 293)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1936 April 1 (Box 21, Folder 294)
    - Carr, Thomas, 1919 December 10 (Box 21, Folder 295)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), 1922 April 24 (Box 21, Folder 296)
    - Dubois, Edward J., 1918 May (Box 21, Folder 297)
    - McVey, J. H., 1924-1933, undated (Box 21, Folder 298)
    - McVey, Margaret, 1931 August 28 (Box 21, Folder 299)
    - "Sophie", 1928–1930 (Box 21, Folder 300)
    - Others, 1892-1936, undated (Box 21, Folder 301-304)
  - Thomas Carr Correspondence
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1905-1923, undated (Box 22, Folder 305-306)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1923–1926 (Box 22, Folder 307)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1890, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 308)
    - Others, 1890–1919 (Box 22, Folder 309)
      Includes letter from Thomas Carr
  - Frances Rosemary (Benét) Dawson Correspondence
    - Others, 1924 January 9 (Box 22, Folder 310)
  - Kathleen Anne (Benét) Fry Correspondence
    - [Benét, James Walker?], undated (Box 22, Folder 311)
    - Others, undated (Box 22, Folder 312)
  - Agnes Mahon Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1918-1929, undated (Box 22, Folder 313)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1923 December 13 (Box 22, Folder 314)
    - Benét, James, 1914-, 1927, undated (Box 22, Folder 315)
    - Benét, Laura, 1918-1926, undated (Box 22, Folder 316)
    - Benét, Rosemary, 1923 December (Box 22, Folder 317)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1918-1927, undated (Box 22, Folder 318)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1905-1917, undated (Box 22, Folder 319)
    - Carr, Rachel H., 1923–1924 (Box 22, Folder 320)
    - Dawson, Frances Rosemary (Benét), 1924-1925, undated (Box 22, Folder 321)
    - Fry, Kathleen Anne (Benét), 1925, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 322)
    - Irwin, John S., 1872 August 13 (Box 22, Folder 323)
    - Mahon, Agnes Mary (Irwin) (mother), 1867–1882 (Box 22, Folder 324)
    - Mahon, [Irwin?] (brother), 1909 January 12 (Box 22, Folder 325)
    - Mahon, Mary (cousin), 1924-1927, undated (Box 22, Folder 326)
    - Mahon, Sophie (sister), 1899 August (Box 22, Folder 327)
    - [Mahon, ?], 1899 August (Box 22, Folder 328)
    - Montgomery, Thomas, 1924-1927, undated (Box 22, Folder 329)
    - Norris, Charles G. (Charles Gilman); Norris, Kathleen Thompson, 1927 December 15 (Box 22, Folder 330)
    - [Rose, Elizabeth Neill?], 1925 (Box 22, Folder 331)
    - Rose, Mary Lee (Mahon), 1909-1915, undated (Box 22, Folder 332)
    - Rose, William John (brother), 1872–1927 (Box 22, Folder 333)
    - Rose, William (nephew), 1924, undated (Box 22, Folder 334)
    - Others, 1882–1923 (Box 22, Folder 335-336)
    - Others, 1923–1925 (Box 23, Folder 337-347)
    - Others, 1925–1927 (Box 24, Folder 348-357)
    - Others, 1927-1929, undated (Box 25, Folder 358-368)
    - Others, undated (Box 26, Folder 369-370)
  - Thomas Montgomery Correspondence
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, undated (Box 26, Folder 371)
  - Agnes Mary Rose Correspondence
    - Rose, William John, 1872 September 6 (Box 26, Folder 372)
    - Others, 1872 (Box 26, Folder 373)
  - Elizabeth Neill Rose Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose (sister), 1914-1925, undated (Box 26, Folder 374-380)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1884-1925, undated (Box 26, Folder 381)
    - Benét, John (nephew), 1886 February 2 (Box 26, Folder 382)
    - Benét, Laura (niece), 1914-1924, undated (Box 26, Folder 383-384)
    - Rose, Mary Lee (mother), 1922 December 14 (Box 26, Folder 385)
    - Rose, William John (brother), 1923 December 17 (Box 26, Folder 386)
    - Others, 1923-1929, undated (Box 26, Folder 387)
  - Mary Lee Rose Correspondence
    - Benét, Frances Rose, 1910, 1915 (Box 27, Folder 388)
    - Benét, Laura, 1904 April 3 (Box 27, Folder 389)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1905–1915 (Box 27, Folder 390)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1902-1914, undated (Box 27, Folder 391-392)
    - Neill, William (grandfather), [?] August 6 (Box 27, Folder 393)
    - Rose, Elizabeth Neill, [18??] (Box 27, Folder 394)
    - Others, 1898-1916, undated (Box 27, Folder 395)
  - [?] Thomson Correspondence
    - Benét, Teresa (Thomson), 1913, undated (Box 27, Folder 396)
  - Katharine Jane Wiest and William H. McCrea Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1884–1890 (Box 27, Folder 397-404)
    - Correspondence, 1891–1895 (Box 28, Folder 405-415)
    - Correspondence, 1895–1896 (Box 29, Folder 416-426)
    - Correspondence, 1896–1897 (Box 30, Folder 427-437)
    - Correspondence, 1897–1899 (Box 31, Folder 438-447)
    - Correspondence, 1899-1900, undated (Box 32, Folder 448-453)
  - Sarah Jane Wiest Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1886-1898, undated (Box 32, Folder 454)
  - Elinor Wylie Correspondence
    - Benét, William Rose, [1920s] (Box 32, Folder 455)
    - Others, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 456)
  - Others and unidentified
    - Correspondence, 1856-1959, undated (Box 32, Folder 457-461)
- Writings, 1849-1973; 1920-1959; 2.83; 3 boxes
  Organized into two subseries: Writings by Members of the Benét Family and Writings of Others.
  Series II. contains writings by members of the Benét family and by others. The small number of works by others relate chiefly to members of the Benét family. Writings by family members includes work by Frances Rose Benét, Laura Benét, Rosemary Benét, Stephen Vincent Benét, Thomas Benét, and William Rose Benét. Drafts and printed versions of mostly shorter works, such as poems, stories, and essays, are present here. The largest group of material, the writings of Laura Benét, includes over 50 titles. Additional writings by Laura Benét can also be found in Series III. Other Papers where, in a subseries for Other Material, scrapbooks include clippings of poems.
  - Writings by Members of the Benét Family
    - Benét, Frances Rose
      - "A Lay Owed to S.V.B.,' poem, autograph manuscript, [1912] (Box 33, Folder 462)
      - "A Merry Christmas to You!," poem, printed version, signed, undated (Box 33, Folder 463)
    - Benét, Laura
      - "Ah, Icarus," poem, printed version, undated (Box 33, Folder 464)
      - Ah, Icarus: Poems, typescript and typescript photocopy, undated (Box 33, Folder 465)
      - "Autobiographical Note," draft, typescript, corrected, [?] October 25 (Box 33, Folder 466)